<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<<info>
  	<name>Items</name>
  	<update version="1.1">
     <file name="items.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/p41c0n/homebrew_dnd/master/items.xml" />
  	</update>
	</info>
	<element name="Tatsumasa, the Dragon's Fang (corrupted)" type="Magic Item"  source="Homebrew" id="ID_MARTIN_HB_MAGIC_ITEM_TATSUMASA_CORRUPTED">		
		<description>
			<p>Die Seele eines Uralten Drachen soll in diesem Schwert gefangen sein.</p>
			<p class="indent">Your weapon attacks with this weapon score a critical hit on a roll of 19 or 20.</p>
			<p class="indent">You gain a +2 bonus to attack rolls and damage rolls you make with this weapon. On a hit with this weapon, the target and the wielder of this weapon take an extra 1d6 necrotic damage.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Homebrew</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="3">3 lb.</set>
			<set name="weapon">Longsword</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
            <set name="enhancement">2</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Ring of Lightning Strikes" type="Magic Item"  source="Homebrew" id="ID_MARTIN_HB_MAGIC_ITEM_RING_OF_LIGHTNING_STRIKES">		
		<description>
			<p>A silver signet ring bearing a stylized Blue Sapphire which emanates an aura of electricity.</p>
			<p class="indent">You gain a +1 bonus to attack rolls you make with unarmed strikes while wearing this ring. On every fourth hit with this weapon, the target takes an extra 2d6 lightning damage.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
            <set name="category">Homebrew</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Ring</set>
            <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
    <element name="Gloves of Radiance" type="Magic Item" source="Homebrew" id="ID_MARTIN_HB_MAGIC_ITEM_GLOVES_OF_RADIANCE">
		<description>
			<p>These gloves are highly conspicuous. They are made of a silvery metal and constantly glow with a bright radiant light.</p>
			<p class="indent">This light grants an advantage on charisma checks not involving deception but imposes disadvantage on all stealth checks   .</p>
			<p class="indent">It provides illumination as a torch.</p>
            <p class="indent">Every point of healing applied via lay on hands while wearing these gloves heals 1 additional point.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Homebrew</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="slot">hands</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
	<element name="Trickster Coin" type="Magic Item" source="Homebrew" id="ID_MARTIN_HB_MAGIC_ITEM_TRICKSTER_COIN">
		<description>
			<p>A gold coin that seems to reflect light in an unnatural and mesmerizing way.</p>
			<p class="indent">When interacting with someone outside of combat, you can begin playing with the coin</p>
			<p class="indent">(Juggling between fingers, flicking it between hands etc.) in an attempt to mesmerize them.</p>
			<p class="indent">The target must make a Wisdom saving throw contested by a Dexterity (Sleight of hand) check </p>
			<p class="indent">or a Dexterity (Performance) check of your choice.</p>
			<p class="indent">On a failed save, the target is stunned by the performance </p>
			<p class="indent">and is completely focused on the coin, ignoring anybody or anything around them.</p>
			<p class="indent">This effect ends after one minute, when you end the coin tricks, or if the target is touched/attacked.</p>
            <p class="indent">On a successful save, the target has no hint you tried to mesmerize them.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Homebrew</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
</elements>